Melissa Costilla

1113 Ironwood Circle Fairfield, CA 94533

(830) 322-9959

melcostilla@gmail.com

Client systems Technicians experienced setting up and maintaining computer systems. Responsible for providing technical assistance and support related to computer systems, hardware, and/or software. respond to queries, run diagnostic programs, isolate problems, and determine and implement solutions. Maintains certification in CompTIA Security+.

SKILLS

- IT Security best practices
 Remote troubleshooting
- Dameware
- Zoom
- Educational psychology
- VM Horizon Client
- GoogleMeets
- Classroom management Technical Help Desk/Customer Project management Service
- Microsoft Office 365
- Enterprise Service Desk (ESD)
- Interpersonal skills

EXPERIENCE

USAF Client Systems Technician, Travis AFB

2018-CURRENT

- Reviews, trains and analyzes methods, procedures and systems used to troubleshoot computer-related issues
- Administers hardware, software and network diagnostic repairs; installs and configures applications system upgrades
- Worked with Senior leadership on VPN client/VMware install for member telework due to COVID-19 shutdown and provided technical assistance to over 2800 military personnel
- Configured and deployed communication devices; ensured proper installation of cables, operating systems and software
- Led onboarding for incoming members to the 349th Air Mobility Wing
- Analyzes and interprets policies and procedures to resolve problems and recommends system improvements
- Management of user domain accounts and security group access for 27 functional units
- Removed and replaced components and peripherals to restore system operation
- Supported users through Zoom.gov during 2020 shutdown
- Conducted One-on-one VMware Installation and training, via Zoom
- Performs independent research and consults with other IT specialists in and out of agency to determine resolutions
- Assisted in digital distribution of 64-Bit Windows 10 images via PXE
- SDC version quarantine
- Identified 300+ 349th AMW specific OrgBoxs from 1000+ basewide listed for deletion, 1 month ahead of schedule

Elementary Art Teacher, Fairfield-Suisun Unified School District

2014-CURRENT

- Utilizes Google applications to facilitate lessons during current distant learning model
- Creates and distributes tutorials on application usage in easy to follow instructions for young learners

- Create and implement lesson plans corresponding to California state and National standards
- Provides mentorship as Team Lead in Elementary Art Program
- Instructed Kindergarten through 8th grade; 3000+ students on 5 campuses simultaneously

Elementary Art Teacher, Northside Independent School District

2011-2013

- Manage classrooms of 25-40, working with a diversified student population
- Designed and facilitated content area curriculum corresponding to Texas state standards
- Instructed Kindergarten through 5th grade students

EDUCATION

University of Texas at SA, San Antonio, TX - BA in Art, 2010

USAF Technical Training School, Keesler Air Force Base, MS, - *Client Systems Technician,* 2018

Certification/Licences

CompTIA Security+, 2019

Military Secret Security Clearance, 2018

Texas Teaching Certificate, 2010

California Teaching Certificate, 2018